A Guide to the Records of Central State Hospital, 1874-1961
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Records of Central State Hospital, 1874-1961
The Library of Virginia
41741
52.4 cu. ft (115 boxes and 6 unboxed volumes)
Central State Hospital
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
The Virginia Freedom of Information Act (Code of Virginia, 2.2-3705.5) and the Virginia Health Records Privacy Act (Code of Virginia, 32.1-172.1:03) establish guidelines for restricting access to medical and other confidential forms of information in order to protect personal privacy. Protected health information (PHI) as defined under the Privacy Regulations issued under the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act (HIPAA) includes, but is not limited to, personally identifiable information such as names, addresses, and social security numbers. The Virginia Public Records Act (Code of Virginia, 42.1-78) includes a provision for closing all privacy protected information for 75 years from the date of creation. In accordance with this legislation, the Library of Virginia can and will restrict, in whole or in part, access to any privacy protected medical information or any other confidential information contained in these records.
Application and admission registers that are less than 75 years old are closed. These registers contain privacy-protected health information that falls under the purview of the Virginia Public Health Records Act (Code of Virginia, 32.1-127.1:03). The registers will remain closed until 75 years after the date of record creation. Records more than 75 years old are open for research.
Acquisition Information
Transferred by Linda C. Coake, Southside Virginia Training Center, 26317 W. Washington St., Warehouse Building 120, Petersburg, Virginia, 23803, 14 February 2005.
Biographical/Historical Information
In 1868, the Freedman's Bureau acquired land known as Howard's Grove, (or Howard Grove), located one half mile east of the city of Richmond, on the Mechanicsville Turnpike, in Henrico County. Through a lease from Mr. Bacon Tait (or Tate), the Bureau renovated several barrack-type structures that had been used as a Confederate hospital during the Civil War. The new facility became known as "Howard's Grove Freedman's Hospital."
The hospital was turned over to the state in December 1869 by way of General Order Number 136 issued by Major General Canby, Military Governor of Virginia. Beginning January 1, 1870 all African American patients at Eastern Lunatic Asylum in Williamsburg, (the only state institution at the time to accept black patients), as well as all jailed black lunatics from across Virginia, were to be removed to Howard's Grove for treatment. The General Assembly passed legislation in June 1870 renaming the facility "Central Lunatic Asylum" and designating it the official "reception and treatment facility for colored persons of unsound mind." This legislation was enacted with the stipulation that the Howard's Grove location was to be temporary.
Many patients arrived at Howard's Grove by way of civil commitments made by local judges at the request of friends and family. Other patients were removed from local jails and criminally committed. The asylum was overseen by a superintendent who answered to the Court of Directors. As with other state institutions, physicians, nurses and matrons were employed to care for patients. The buildings at Howard's Grove during the period of 1870 to 1885 were described as being of plain, if not crude, wood construction. They were divided into sections according to the patient's particular ailment or behavior. Residents were fed in their cells, as no dining facility existed at that time. There was no sewage system, and light was supplied by kerosene lamps and candles.
In order to enlarge the institution and alleviate the poor living conditions, a 300 acre tract of land was purchased in March 1882 by the City of Petersburg and given to the state for the purpose of constructing a permanent mental health facility for African Americans. According to the Acts of Assembly, the new hospital was built on land previously known as Hare's Farm or New Market, on the outskirts of Petersburg, in Prince George County. This information is disputed by William Drewry, a former superintendent and institutional historian who contends that the site chosen was actually the Mayfield farm in Dinwiddie County. The historical marker placed at the site also states that the hospital is located on the grounds of the former Mayfield Plantation.
Construction of the new facility near Petersburg was completed in early spring 1885. Additional tracts of land were purchased and new buildings were constructed regularly thereafter, as the number of patients increased. The new construction later included a special building to house the criminally insane apart from the rest of the hospital population. This section of the campus would later be referred to as the Forensic Mental Health Unit. An early institutional history notes that treatment at Central Lunatic Asylum during the 1890s was humane and emphasized the value of work and the benefits of recreation. However, practices at the facility also included seclusion, mechanical restraints, and the administering of hypnotics.
In 1894, Central Lunatic Asylum was officially renamed Central State Hospital. This piece of legislation also altered the names of the other mental health facilities in Virginia in and atttempt to inspire a more positive image of the institutions, and of mental health treatment in general. It is important to note that another state institution located in Staunton, Virginia went by the name Central Lunatic Asylum between the years of 1861 and 1865. Its name was later changed to Western Lunatic Asylum, and is a separate facility with no connection to the Richmond/Petersburg hospital for African Americans.
Following the trend to separate patients based on illness and behavior, the General Assembly authorized the establishment of a colony for feeble-minded people in March 1938. The act established the colony as a state institution separate from Central State Hospital, though still located on the same grounds. Known as the Petersburg State Colony, the new facility was given land located in Prince George County (later partly in Dinwiddie County as well), and assigned the task of admitting mostly younger patients with the propensity for academic and vocational training and future employment. Through a 1954 Act of Assembly, the Petersburg State Colony was renamed the Petersburg Training School and Hospital. The name was changed again in 1971 to the Southside Virginia Training Center. The facility moved from its original buildings in the early 1960s, but still remains part of the Central State Hospital campus. It continues to specialize in providing services for Virginians with various levels of mental retardation. As a side note, in 1960 the land and structures formally known as the Petersburg Training School and Hospital were transferred to the College of William and Mary for the establishment of a two-year branch campus. In 1961, Richard Bland College opened its doors to students. The original hospital buildings remained, but were converted into classrooms and offices, many of which are still in use.
In later years, the burgeoning patient population at Central State Hospital began to outgrow all the additions and improvements made over the preceding decades. The average resident population in 1948 was nearly 4,00, with overcrowding serving as the hospital's biggest obstacle. By 1950, the ward known as East View reportedly housed more than 300 patients in one large room. In the Criminal Building, conditions were so cramped that patients slept on the floor. As a result of the overcrowding, several new buildings were constructed during the 1950s and 1960s to house patients more comfortably, and in settings more conducive to the treatment of specific illnesses and age groups. During this period the hospital enhanced its services to include substance abuse recovery programs and specialized geriatric treatment.
The Civil Rights Act of 1964 radically changed the face of Central State Hospital. This piece of federal legislation forced the Commonwealth of Virginia to desegregate public facilities and provide equal services to all residents. For the first time in its nearly 100 year history, Central State Hospital opened its doors to individuals of every race. By the early 1990s the racial make-up of the institution was split almost evenly between whites and blacks with 49.8% of patients classified as "white," 49.2% classified as "black," and 1% as "other."
Central State Hospital still operates as a state-run institution in the same general location as it did in 1885. Though its clientele, medical practices, and appearance have changed over time, the mission of Central State Hospital remains much the same: "to provide state of the art mental health care and treatment to forensic and civilly committed patients" in central Virginia.
Central State Hospital has fallen under the heading of many different departments since its establishment. Over the years it has been controlled by the Court of Directors (later called the State Hospital Board), the Department of Mental Hygiene and Hospitals, the Department of Mental Health and Hygiene, and the Department of Mental Health and Mental Retardation. Currently, the hospital falls under the jurisdiction of the Department of Mental Health, Mental Retardation and Substance Abuse Services.
Scope and Content
Contains a variety of records including application and admission registers, commitment papers, construction contracts and building specifications, deeds, furloughs and bonds, insurance records, aerial site plans, minutes of the General Board of Directors, and reports of the Special Boards of the other mental health institutions in Virginia. The majority of the records are commitment papers.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the following series:
Series I. Application and Admission Registers, 1919-1961
Series II. Commitment Papers, 1874-1906
Series III. Construction Records, 1904-1938
Series IV. Deeds and Leases, 1882-1942
Series V. Furloughs and Bonds, 1903-1911
Series VI. Insurance Records, 1924-1958
Series VII. Minutes of the General Board of Directors, 1920-1936
Series VIII. Reports of the Special Boards, 1920-1936
Contents List
- Series I. Application and Admission Registers, 1919-1961. (Volumes 1-7.)
  Registers contain lists of applicants to Central State Hospital on a monthly basis. Entries include the applicant's name, age, place of residence, date the application was received, and the date the person was admitted into the hospital, if he or she was accepted. The registers do not contain much in the way of personal or medical information about patients, except for notes as to whether the patient was in jail or out on bond, feeble-minded or epileptic, suicidal or a criminal. Application and admission registers that are less than 75 years old are closed. These registers contain privacy-protected health information that falls under the purview of the Virginia Public Health Records Act (Code of Virginia, 32.1-127.1:03). The registers will remain closed until 75 years after the date of record creation.
  Arranged chronologically.
  - 1919-1925. (Volume 1)
  - 1925-1933. (Volume 2)
  - 1934-1941. (Volume 3)
  - 1941-1948. (Volume 4)
  - 1948-1954. (Volume 5)
  - 1954-1958. (Volume 6)
  - 1958-1961. (Volume 7)
- Series II. Commitment Papers, 1874-1906. (Box 1-107.)
  Contains commitment papers that were originally folded into standard sized envelopes with patient name, admission date, and register number written on the front. The papers were removed from the envelopes and flat-filed. The commitment papers usually include depositions from doctors, friends and family attesting to the patient's mental state, as well as other legal documents, and sometimes brief correspondence. Beginning around 1902, many of the files also contain a "Report of New Patient" which contains information about the patient upon his/her arrival at the hospital, including height, weight, level of cleanliness, record of clothing or valuables brought, and general notes as to the patient's condition. In some cases, medical records are also included with the commitment papers. At the end of the box and folder list for this series is a small group of rejected applications dated 1905-1907.
  Arranged by year of commitment and then alphabetically within.
  - 1874.
    - A. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - B. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - B. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - C. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - C. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - D-E. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - F. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - G. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - H. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - J. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - J. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - L. (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - M. (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - P. (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - R-S. (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - T. (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - W. (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - W. (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - W. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - 1875.
    - A. (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - B. (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - B. (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - C. (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - C. (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - D-F. (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - G. (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - H. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - H. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - J. (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - K-L. (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - M. (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - N-O. (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - P. (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - R. (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - S. (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - S. (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - T. (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - V. (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - W. (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - W. (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - 1876.
    - B. (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - C. (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - F-G. (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - H. (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - J-L. (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - M. (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - N-P. (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - R-T. (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - 1877.
    - B. (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - C-D. (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - E-F. (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - G. (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - H. (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - J-K. (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - L. (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - M. (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - N-O. (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - P. (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - R. (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - S-W. (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - 1878.
    - A. (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - B. (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - C. (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - D. (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - F. (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - G. (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - H. (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - J. (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - L-M. (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - O-P. (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - S. (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - T-W. (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - 1879.
    - A. (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - B. (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - C-E. (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - G. (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - J-K. (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - L. (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - M. (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - P. (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - R. (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - S. (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - S. (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - T. (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - W. (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - 1880.
    - J. (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - 1881.
    - A. (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - A. (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - B. (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - B. (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - B. (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - C. (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - C. (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - C. (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - D. (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - D. (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - E-F. (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - G. (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - G. (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - H. (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - H. (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - J. (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - J. (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - K-L. (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - M. (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - M. (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - M. (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Mc. (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - N. (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - P. (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - R. (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - S. (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - S. (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - T. (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - T. (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - T. (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - U. (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - W. (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - W. (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - W. (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - 1882.
    - A. (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - B. (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - B. (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - C-D. (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - F. (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - G. (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - H. (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - J. (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - L. (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - M. (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - N-O. (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - P. (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - R. (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - S. (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - T. (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - W. (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - List of Old Cases Discharged from or Died in Jail. (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - 1883.
    - A. (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - B. (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - B. (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - C. (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - C. (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - D. (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - E. (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - F. (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - F. (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - G. (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - G. (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - H. (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - H. (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - H. (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - J. (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - J. (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - K. (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - L. (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - M. (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - N. (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - P. (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - P. (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - R. (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - R. (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - S. (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - S. (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - T-U. (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - W. (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - W. (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - 1884.
    - B. (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - B. (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - B. (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - C. (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - C. (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - D-E. (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - F. (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - F. (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - G. (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - H. (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - H. (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - H. (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - J. (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - J. (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - K. (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - L. (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - M. (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - M. (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - N. (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - P. (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - P. (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Q-R. (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - S. (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - S. (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - S. (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - T. (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - T. (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - V. (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - W. (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - W. (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - W. (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - 1885.
    - A. (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - B. (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - B. (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - B. (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - C. (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - C. (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - C. (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - D. (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - D. (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - F. (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - F. (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - G. (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - H. (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - H. (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - H. (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - I. (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - J. (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - J. (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - J. (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - K. (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - L. (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - M. (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - M. (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - N. (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - P. (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - P. (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - P. (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - R. (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - S. (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - S. (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - S. (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - T. (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - W. (Box 18, Folder 13)
    - W. (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - W. (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Y. (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - 1886.
    - A. (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - B. (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - B. (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - C. (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - C. (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - C. (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - C. (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - D-E. (Box 19, Folder 11)
    - F. (Box 19, Folder 12)
    - G. (Box 19, Folder 13)
    - G. (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - H. (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - H. (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - J. (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - J. (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - J. (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - K. (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - L. (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - L. (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - M. (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - M. (Box 20, Folder 11)
    - N. (Box 20, Folder 12)
    - P. (Box 20, Folder 13)
    - R. (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - S. (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - S. (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - T. (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - T. (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - U (unknown). (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - W. (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - W. (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - W. (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - 1887.
    - A-B. (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - C. (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - C. (Box 21, Folder 12)
    - D. (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - E. (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - F. (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - G. (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - H. (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - H. (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - J. (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - J. (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - K. (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - L. (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - M. (Box 22, Folder 11)
    - N-O. (Box 22, Folder 12)
    - P-R. (Box 22, Folder 13)
    - S. (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - S. (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - T. (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - T. (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - W. (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - W. (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - 1888.
    - A. (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - A. (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - B. (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - B. (Box 23, Folder 10)
    - B. (Box 23, Folder 11)
    - B. (Box 23, Folder 12)
    - B. (Box 23, Folder 13)
    - C. (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - C. (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - C. (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - C. (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - C. (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - D. (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - D. (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - E. (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - F. (Box 24, Folder 9)
    - G. (Box 24, Folder 10)
    - G. (Box 24, Folder 11)
    - G. (Box 24, Folder 12)
    - H. (Box 24, Folder 13)
    - H. (Box 24, Folder 14)
    - H. (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - J. (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - J. (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - J. (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - K. (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - L. (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - L. (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - M. (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - M. (Box 25, Folder 9)
    - M. (Box 25, Folder 10)
    - Mc. (Box 25, Folder 11)
    - N-O. (Box 25, Folder 12)
    - P. (Box 25, Folder 13)
    - P. (Box 25, Folder 14)
    - P. (Box 25, Folder 15)
    - R. (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - R. (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - S. (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - S. (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - S. (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - S. (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - S. (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - T. (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - T. (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - T. (Box 26, Folder 10)
    - V. (Box 26, Folder 11)
    - W. (Box 26, Folder 12)
    - W. (Box 26, Folder 13)
    - W. (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - W. (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - Y. (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - 1889.
    - A. (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - B. (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - B. (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - B. (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - C. (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - C. (Box 27, Folder 9)
    - D. (Box 27, Folder 10)
    - D. (Box 27, Folder 11)
    - E. (Box 27, Folder 12)
    - F. (Box 27, Folder 13)
    - F. (Box 27, Folder 14)
    - G. (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - H. (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - H. (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - I. (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - J. (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - K. (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - L. (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - M. (Box 28, Folder 8)
    - M. (Box 28, Folder 9)
    - M. (Box 28, Folder 10)
    - N. (Box 28, Folder 11)
    - P. (Box 28, Folder 12)
    - P. (Box 28, Folder 13)
    - R. (Box 28, Folder 14)
    - R. (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - S. (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - S. (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - S. (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - T. (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - T. (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - W. (Box 29, Folder 7)
    - W. (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - 1890.
    - A. (Box 29, Folder 9)
    - B. (Box 29, Folder 10)
    - B. (Box 29, Folder 11)
    - B. (Box 29, Folder 12)
    - B. (Box 29, Folder 13)
    - B. (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - B. (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - C. (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - C. (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - C. (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - C. (Box 30, Folder 6)
    - D. (Box 30, Folder 7)
    - E. (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - F. (Box 30, Folder 9)
    - G. (Box 30, Folder 10)
    - G. (Box 30, Folder 11)
    - G. (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - H. (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - H. (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - H. (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - J. (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - J. (Box 31, Folder 6)
    - J. (Box 31, Folder 7)
    - K. (Box 31, Folder 8)
    - L. (Box 31, Folder 9)